<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<measure xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://bcl.nrel.gov/xsd/measures/version/1.0.xsd"><name>Set Air-Cooled Air Conditioner COP</name><uid>a7b70ba5-72e9-440d-a9e1-7e209902ed16</uid><version_id>80a7b9c6-0db7-4280-ba8f-6a8abb30445c</version_id><description>Air conditioner coefficient of performance (COP) affects cooling  energy consumption. The measure offers two options to set the air-cooled air conditioner COP. Option 1 allows users to specify the COP input directly. Option 2 determines the COP based on the rated total cooling capacity and the prescriptive requirements in ASHRAE Standard 90.1. </description><modeler_description>The measure loops through the baseline model and identifies the OS:Coil:Cooling:DX:SingleSpeed and OS:Coil:Cooling:DX:TwoSpeed objects. The measure is applicable to the cooling coils only if the coil is part of an air loop that contains an OS:Coil:Heating:Electric, OS:Coil:Heating:Gas, OS:Coil:Heating:Water, or no heating coil object. Users can choose one or all cooling coils from the drop down list to change their rated COP settings. Then users need to select Option 1 or 2 using the check box. For Option 1, a rated COP input is required and it is applied to the selected cooling coils. For Option 2, users need to specify the rated total cooling capacity and the version of Standard 90.1. These inputs are used to identify the COP requirement in the Standard 90.1, which is used to change the model. The initial and final values of the COP are reported during simulation.</modeler_description><tags><tag>HVAC.Cooling</tag></tags><attributes><attribute><name>Measure Type</name><value>ModelMeasure</value><datatype>string</datatype></attribute><attribute><name>Measure Function</name><value>Measure</value><datatype>string</datatype></attribute><attribute><name>Requires EnergyPlus Results</name><value>false</value><datatype>boolean</datatype></attribute><attribute><name>Uses SketchUp API</name><value>false</value><datatype>boolean</datatype></attribute></attributes><files><file><filename>SetAirCooledAirConditionerCOP_Test.rb</filename><filetype>rb</filetype><usage_type>test</usage_type><checksum>F8A77E5C</checksum></file><file><version><software_program>OpenStudio</software_program><identifier>1.0.0</identifier></version><filename>measure.rb</filename><filetype>rb</filetype><usage_type>script</usage_type><checksum>AE443A63</checksum></file></files></measure>